<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>City of Wings - Ideas</title><link href="https://city.shaform.com/en/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://city.shaform.com/en/feeds/ideas.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://city.shaform.com/en/</id><updated>2014-11-07T18:52:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>Google Inbox-like Web Browsing</title><link href="https://city.shaform.com/en/blog/2014/11/07/google-inbox-like-web-browsing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-11-07T18:52:00+08:00</published><updated>2014-11-07T18:52:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Shaform</name></author><id>tag:city.shaform.com,2014-11-07:/en/blog/2014/11/07/google-inbox-like-web-browsing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last time, I explored the idea of designing a web browsing UI that reduces the possibility of distractions in &lt;a href="https://city.shaform.com/en/blog/2013/10/20/single-minded.html"&gt;〈Single-minded : an Internet reader, made for readers, made by readers〉&lt;/a&gt;. While that idea might sound interesting, the design itself was somewhat primitive. Recently, Google has announced &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/inbox/"&gt;Inbox&lt;/a&gt;, a new way to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last time, I explored the idea of designing a web browsing UI that reduces the possibility of distractions in &lt;a href="https://city.shaform.com/en/blog/2013/10/20/single-minded.html"&gt;〈Single-minded : an Internet reader, made for readers, made by readers〉&lt;/a&gt;. While that idea might sound interesting, the design itself was somewhat primitive. Recently, Google has announced &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/inbox/"&gt;Inbox&lt;/a&gt;, a new way to handle email. And I find that many ideas behind Inbox are also applicable to web browsing as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tabs as Threads&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, different tabs can be represented as different threads, and for each thread, the history can be easily represented as different 'email' in the same thread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="History as emails" src="https://city.shaform.com/en/images/inbox-history.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such layout provides better navigation for histories than the current design of 'back' and 'forward' buttons. Sophisticated text summarization techniques can also be used to enable user to get information without actually open that page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Search as Threads&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only a tab can be represented as threads, a search attempt can also utilize the thread layout. We simply click on the empty space, and a search input field would appear. After entering the keywords, we click as many results as we like. Each click results in a different 'email' in the same threads, and we can inspect each one later at any time. We can archive unrelavent pages and decide to mark every remaining results with a label for later use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Unification of History, Bookmarks, and Tabs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, every page marked as done (archived) is just like the old history. Every page on the inbox is just like the tabs. And every page with a label is a bookmark. In this way, we unify everything with a consistent and simple UI. We also drastically increase the possibility for the user to utilize bookmark functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We Learn Everything, so We Search for You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we can safely assume that any pages left in the inbox is something that the user is interested in currently. (Otherwise she should have archived it.) We can actively recommend related pages for different threads. Moreover, for those 'search threads', we also have the keywords used, and since the user might try to delete unwanted results from the inbox, we have relevance feedback as well. And latency is no longer an issue, as we can do the search and the show results when the user open the browser next time. So we are able to produce extremely accurate result compared to conventional search engines. And we also have the opportunity to insert related advertisment as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if we do use this kind of web browsing, our entire browsing history will be on the cloud. Is this acceptable?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="browser"></category><category term="Internet"></category><category term="Google Inbox"></category></entry><entry><title>Single-minded : an Internet reader, made for readers, made by readers</title><link href="https://city.shaform.com/en/blog/2013/10/20/single-minded.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-20T20:25:00+08:00</published><updated>2013-10-20T20:25:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Shaform</name></author><id>tag:city.shaform.com,2013-10-20:/en/blog/2013/10/20/single-minded.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Realization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've known it for a long time that it’s difficult for me to read long articles on the web. I thought it’s because of the screen. It made my eyes get tired so easily. However, when I started to read The Shallows written by Nicholas Carr, I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Realization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've known it for a long time that it’s difficult for me to read long articles on the web. I thought it’s because of the screen. It made my eyes get tired so easily. However, when I started to read The Shallows written by Nicholas Carr, I realized that it’s not only the screen. The Internet itself is distracting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started to remember that, I often clicked between different tabs aimlessly. I repeatedly opened and reopened the Facebook page or my email inbox, wasting my time getting nothing. Indeed, I realized that I was so impatient that whenever the browser was loading a new page, I would switch to another tab, because I did not want to wait for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I noticed this, I started to think about possible solutions to overcome this problem -- a new way of browsing. If I could get rid of the waiting time, maybe tabs would no longer be needed? If I could get rid of the tabs, maybe the Internet would be less distracting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Single-tasking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To focus on one time at a time when browsing, the first thing I would need to change is the bookmarks. Bookmarks are distracting. Whenever I open the browser, I need to choose between different websites, and this decision is difficult to make. Indeed, because those tiny icons always compete for my attention, I get distracted easily and forget my tasks. Instead of choosing between different websites, I should simply choose between Tasks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Tasks" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/F7oAKl0sAyFqQPubG8gUytcYkQgLJM0LlejSH9SmTIxXB95BZ2_KvyaxXFVFdGErcv9VABjNiV8tRBo0t3vsqKiF7zA-0jxirAgBbBV5kWqmxe8-2N7kvcI0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each Task is composed of multiple Steps, and each Step has its own history of pages. When I click on one Task, the browser would only display one page: the last viewed page of the first Step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Step" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/lyQGxP6oxBwAYs-lTUE8ND5oXe0Uo-ryYkLkODjKC9D-HVsGGhP5lFcX_HLbVO4VpSwrwPwCCvpmb9ztOJEQUMLt3NyXrHulMi8r8vleF_0mMIRB0tTSIGJs"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It shouldn't be allowed to open two Tasks at the same time. I must complete one Task before I can go to the home page again. This makes me focus on one thing at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Never Going Back&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I am in a Step, I can go back and forth through history within the Step as usual. But once I proceed to the next Step, there is no going back. This design forces me to focus on one Step at a time and encourages me to complete one Step before I go on to the next. But of course, sometimes I may want to read some other references before I can complete a Step. In this case, I can push the current Step to the end of the current Task, so I can come back to it later. By pushing everything to the end, I can actually keep every Step open, but even in this case, a linear flow is still maintained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I have no tabs, I cannot open a new page in a different tab. Instead, I open it in the current Step or in a new Step. For example, when I am reading an article, I can look up unfamiliar words in new Steps, so I can finish the current article and then look at those definitions later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="New Steps" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/0oWiT3Xjw5XPluesbq_B07Mlvr2nNMy_27YxkiOIsE_gZauVwklXssKV3SE7rhWjoHd58SSae56WqiK9AeG4fHcrrWQQn-LoX-o5P8Cbnb_OFWAcbtEzeIJD"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Manage the Tasks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I complete one Task, I go back to the home screen. At that time, I have the opportunity to merge my history into the original Task or create a new one. In addition, I should have an intuitive interface to easily manage the Tasks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Manage the Tasks" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/fZevhXmTij2mqmE_lFwg-qkLMlRfqoHsolYj2ngSaanJFsj1KBzGnLgnargdKH-krqe_b5w5PzxfACJL3ePK3uPzR4CqF7mzXwWgOZ_qBbfKSRgxy2wvQRM7"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A New Way to Utilize History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;History is a seldom used feature. Actually, sorting web pages by visited time simply does not make sense. Sometimes I want to find some pages that I visited before, but it’s often extremely difficult to locate the exact position in history. However, with Single-minded, the history is naturally grouped for each task. It’s easy to guess where the page might be. Also, because I can preserve all history into Tasks if I want, history becomes an useful feature that I can utilize to better manage my Tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Never Waiting for Loading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The linear browsing makes it easy for the browser to guess which page I will read next. So it should be easy for the browser to preload the pages and completely eliminate the waiting time for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Final Words&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I choose to publish this article because I realize that I may not have too much time to polish this idea and implement it. As you can see, this article is still very primitive. But I hope someone may be able to find something valuable in this idea, and help us escape from the distracting dilemma.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="browser"></category><category term="Internet"></category></entry></feed>